Zoe: The benefit of close working
relationships and partnerships when I'm
supporting children and young people
with autism is the sort of consistency
across the support that the child
is being offered and ensuring that
how the people that are working with
them in lots of different settings
are working with them in the same way
to sort of help their development.
I also think it's really important in
terms of making decisions and making sure
that the decisions are all being made with
the benefit of the child or young person.
Ellen: We all work together.
We've all got different knowledge
from different backgrounds.
So obviously when you've got a lot
of different people with different
knowledge and you work together,
you know, you help fill the gaps.
Zoe T: To get real meaningful benefits
with professionals, you need to have
a shared framework of understanding
about what your goals are and what
your understanding of autism is.
Phil: I think it really has a direct
correlation to the progress, personal
progress, our pupils make, but
also the progress they make in the
classroom because their sensory diet,
their sensory needs are better met.
So rather than just having, as you would
in a mainstream school, a class teacher
who would differentiate according to
the needs of their pupils, but rather
just having, sort of,  academic targets,
if you like, there's a wider - the
wider needs of the learners, are met.
Kerry: It's about getting that specialist
input from other places as well because as
a teacher, obviously I was trained for the
academic side and the academic support.
Whereas when I can work with speech
and language therapists, they can
help me on the communication side.
An occupational therapist might
be able to help me with the
self-regulation side of it.
I think it's really important that we
work with as many teams as possible to get
that overarching support to every level.
Phil: Well, we follow the teach approach.
So all the tasks are clearly
labeled -  this is task one, this
is task two, this is task three, and
then finished or choose activity.
Visual schedules, so our pupils
always know what they're doing now
and what's coming next and who with.
Kerry: It's that holistic approach.
It's making sure that we are doing
the best for the people we support
in every area of their life.